export const PICTUREMAKINGA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Warm colours in a composition are perceived to",
A: "advance.",
B: "form the primaries.",
C: "form the secondaries.",
D: "recede.",
answer: "A. advance.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The brightness of a colour is termed",
A: "intensity.",
B: "neutral.",
C: "tone.",
D: "value.",
answer: "A. intensity.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The basic identity of a colour is referred to as",
A: "chroma.",
B: "hue.",
C: "intensity.",
D: "value.",
answer: "B. hue.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of these create stability in a composition?",
A: "Balance",
B: "Dominance",
C: "Rhythm",
D: "Size",
answer: "A. Balance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Select the two main sources of colour from the following pairs.",
A: "Cool and warm",
B: "Pigment and light",
C: "Primary and secondary",
D: "Tint and shade",
answer: "B. Pigment and light",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A beam of light passing through a glass prism produce",
A: "achromatic colours,",
B: "secondary colours.",
C: "spectrum colours.",
D: "tertiary colours.",
answer: "C. spectrum colours.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of these options help in the organisation of a composition?",
A: "Colour",
B: "Contrast",
C: "Shape",
D: "Size",
answer: "B. Contrast",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The trail left behind by the tip of a tool from one point to the another is referred to as a",
A: "horizon.",
B: "line.",
C: "pattern.",
D: "rhythm.",
answer: "B. line.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Acrylic paint is to water as encaustic paint is to",
A: "lacquer.",
B: "linseed oil.",
C: "molten wax.",
D: "turpentine.",
answer: "C. molten wax.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Canvas is primed before painting to make the",
A: "design visible.",
B: "paint stick.",
C: "work bright.",
D: "work matty.",
answer: "B. pores will be sealed.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The best tool used for scraper board work is",
A: "bodkin.",
B: "bone folder.",
C: "palette knife.",
D: "stylus.",
answer: "D. stylus.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The exposed area on a screen for printing is referred to as the",
A: "copy.",
B: "stencil.",
C: "template.",
D: "unit.",
answer: "B. stencil.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. In frottage, the print is obtained directly by",
A: "marbling,",
B: "painting.",
C: "rubbing.",
D: "tracing.",
answer: "C. rubbing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The tool used to spread photo emulsion directly to the screen is a",
A: "brush.",
B: "pallete knife.",
C: "roller",
D: "scoop coater",
answer: "C. roller",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. When the printing area on a block drops below the surface, it is referred to as",
A: "frottage.",
B: "intaglio,",
C: "relief.",
D: "serigraphy.",
answer: "B. intaglio.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Select a picture maker from the following artists.",
A: "E. Owusu-Dartey",
B: "J. K. Amoah",
C: "Kojo Ofosu",
D: "R. C. Ekem",
answer: "A. E. Owusu-Dartey",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The final stage in watercolour painting is",
A: "drawing.",
B: "mounting.",
C: "sketching.",
D: "sponging.",
answer: "B. mounting.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The main difference between watercolour and oil painting is that the latter is",
A: "colourful.",
B: "matt.",
C: "opaque.",
D: "transparent.",
answer: "C. opaque.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Select a binder from the following options.",
A: "Glue",
B: "Turpentine",
C: "Water",
D: "Wax",
answer: "A. Glue",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. In the options provided, the first factor to consider before executing a painting is the",
A: "sketches.",
B: "style.",
C: "technique.",
D: "theme.",
answer: "D. theme.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. In a landscape drawing, which of the following areas require more detail?",
A: "Background",
B: "Foreground",
C: "Horizon",
D: "Sky",
answer: "B. Foreground",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Unlike poster colour, watercolour painting is executed from",
A: "dark to light colours.",
B: "light to dark colours.",
C: "low to high key colours.",
D: "warm to cool colours,",
answer: "B. light to dark colours.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following artists was influenced by African sculpture?",
A: "Buonarotti Michelangelo",
B: "Leonardo da Vinci",
C: "Pablo Picasso",
D: "Vincent Van Gogh",
answer: "C. Pablo Picasso",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. In computer graphics, which of the following is a vector imaging application?",
A: "Adobe photoshop",
B: "Coral draw",
C: "Coral photoshop",
D: "Paint box",
answer: "B. Coral draw",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Select the quickest technique for executing a painting from the options.",
A: "Alla prima",
B: "Encaustic",
C: "Scumbling",
D: "Sgraffito",
answer: "A. Alla prima",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The tool for spreading the paint for block printing is",
A: "brush.",
B: "roller.",
C: "scoop coater.",
D: "squeegee,",
answer: "D. squeegee,",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which picture making technique involves burning on surfaces?",
A: "Engraving",
B: "Marquetry",
C: "Pyrography",
D: "Serigraphy",
answer: "C. Pyrography",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The nvo-point perspective is also referred to as",
A: "aerial.",
B: "angular.",
C: "parallel.",
D: "oblique.",
answer: "B. angular.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following requires critical observation in drawing? A",
A: "landscape drawing.",
B: "sketch of the lorry park.",
C: "still-life drawing in abstract.",
D: "study of the human face.",
answer: "D. study of the human face.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Animation is",
A: "drawing animate objects.",
B: "drawing satirical images.",
C: "giving life to still images.",
D: "taking quick pictures.",
answer: "C. giving life to still images.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The afterimage of black is",
A: "blue.",
B: "orange.",
C: "yellow.",
D: "white.",
answer: "D. white.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Porous supports for murals are prepared with",
A: "lacquer.",
B: "linseed oil.",
C: "turpentine.",
D: "P.V.A glue.",
answer: "D. P.V.A glue.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Acomposition created from several pictures is referred to as",
A: "collage.",
B: "frieze.",
C: "montage.",
D: "mosaic.",
answer: "C. montage.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which art movement concerned itself with irrational painting?",
A: "Cubism",
B: "Dadaism",
C: "Futurism",
D: "Surrealism",
answer: "D. Surrealism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Incomputing, the graphic user interface that pops up is the",
A: "docker.",
B: "flyout.",
C: "navigator,",
D: "toolbox.",
answer: "D. toolbox.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Blending tones of colours with no clear demarcation is",
A: "alla prima,",
B: "chiaroscuro,",
C: "sfumato.",
D: "Sgraffito,",
answer: "C. sfumato.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Paintings done on panels and fixed on walls are technically reffered to as",
A: "fresco.",
B: "frieze,",
C: "marouflage.",
D: "mural,",
answer: "D. mural.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The price ofa painting is mainly influenced by",
A: "demand and Jabour cost.",
B: "demand and production cost.",
C: "production and advertising cost.",
D: "utility and labour cost.",
answer: "B. demand and production cost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Museums and galleries are similar in that, both keep custody of",
A: "archival pieces,",
B: "art works.",
C: "important relics.",
D: "written documents.",
answer: "B. art works.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A painted canvas fixed to a wall by applying adhesive is",
A: "fresco.",
B: "frieze.",
C: "marouflage.",
D: "photomontage.",
answer: "C. marouflage.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]